

Biography

Name: Wittawas Wisarnkanchana

Nick Name: Start

Email: <u>start@wittawasw.com</u> Website: <u>blog.wittawasw.com</u>

Github: wittawasw

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/wittawasw

Tel: +668-7769-2527

Age: 26

Nationality: Thai

Language: Thai, English

Current Location: Chiang Rai, Thailand

Education

Bachelor Degree of Computer Engineering, Kasetsart University

Work Experiences

Cofounder and Software developer, Decho Tech, 2011 - 2013

Lead planning and development, AssetP, 2012 - 2014

Lead Software Developer codemy.net, 2014 - 2015

DevOps Seer, Connectica Directory Services, June 2015 - October 2015

Active Communities

Angular Developer Thailand, Developer Advocate, 2014 - present

Wittawas Wisarnkanchana

TDLR;

I'm a software developer who prefer to use Ruby more than any other languages but recently grow fond of Go and Elixir. Have knowledges about server and architecture that can be used in production.

About me

In late 2014, I joined <u>codemy.net</u> as a senior developer for a long-term contract to lead on building their new product using Ruby on Rails and various technologies on AWS.

My role in <u>codemy.net</u> is focused on develop strategies and techniques to use in their products such as deciding on which structures or libraries should be used or should be deprecated from legacy code.

Working on enterprise class requirements on this project required us to use cloud provider that can cover our growth and at the same time have a good enough reputation to make our initial client feel secure. We chose to invest in AWS.

We shift all of our technologies stack toward AWS after the decision but chose to remain some of development environments in our own house. This time I have to focus heavily on develop suitable deployment process since our stack is getting more complex each day of development.

In early 2015, our product, an enterprise class searchservices have secure financial supports and gaining more attentions. We decided to spin-off this product into another company to focus more on this product. I left the company to live in Chiang Rai in October 2015.

Right now, I'm working remotely for an oversea client who want to improve their Ruby on Rails code quality and migrate their servers to AWS architecture.

Volunteering

- Speaker, Instructor for tech events or schools.
- Free consulting and development for non-profit organizations.

Skills set

- Design overall architecture for high-availability platform using AWS and other cloud providers.
- -Web application developments using frameworks (prefer Ruby on Rails).
- Backend development using various technologies based on requirements (prefer Ruby, Elixir)
- Front-end application development using Javascript, CSS. (prefer non-framework JS, Angular, SASS).
- Planning using scrum board and agile methodology.
- Unit testing and End-to-end testing using Rspec, Capybara.
- DevOps skill sets on Amazon EC2 and other cloud providers.
- Design deployment process over complex infrastructure using Capistrano, Ansible and AWS OpsWork (formerly using Chef).
- Using MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Cassandra in development and production as a persistence database.
- Data manipulation using Apache Spark.
- Manage clustered environments using Apache Mesos